<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Miao Zhang&#39;s personal website</title>
    <link>https://miaozhang.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Miao Zhang&#39;s personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://miaozhang.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Montreal Forced Aligner Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://miaozhang.org/event/mfa-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaozhang.org/event/mfa-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This tutorial of Montreal Forced Alignment was given at the Pakistan Association of Phonetics and Phonology Scholars (PAPPS).&#xA;You can download the slides &lt;a href=&#34;https://miaozhang.org/2025-04-28-montreal-forced-aligner-tutorial/index.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the materials [here]/2025-04-28-montreal-forced-aligner-tutorial/MFA_tutorial_MZ_2025.zip).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic seeding formant extraction</title>
      <link>https://miaozhang.org/post/2024/02/26/dynamic-seeding-praat-script-bundle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaozhang.org/post/2024/02/26/dynamic-seeding-praat-script-bundle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-dynamic-seeding-formant-extracting-script-bundle&#34;&gt;1. Dynamic seeding formant extracting script bundle&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script bundle incorporated the seeding method (Chen et al. 2019)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and dynamic formant reference value settings to extract more accurate formants from vocalic segments. Three scripts are found in this bundle:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The formant extraction script that uses dynamic seeding to extract formants without step-wise optimization&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The formant extraction script that uses dynamic seeding to extract formants and does step-wise optimization, iterating over a range of ceiling frequencies (manually set by the user).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The script that extracts spectral tilt measures such as H1-H2, H2-H4, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since my study investigates the formant transition in complex vocalic segments (e.g., diphthongs/triphthongs), the usual method of setting only one set of reference formant values and ignoring the formant excursions in vocalic segments is not ideal. Also, because there are different vocalic segments in my recordings (both monophthongs and diphthongs), manually setting formant reference values for each vowel and each speaker each time when doing the analysis is meticulous and arduous. Therefore, I decided to combine the seeding method and dynamic formant reference setting into one single Praat script that loops through all files in all subdirectories in a root folder, making formant extraction much faster and more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consonant-induced F0 perturbation in Kansai Japanese</title>
      <link>https://miaozhang.org/event/consonant-induced-f0-perturbation-in-kansai-japanese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaozhang.org/event/consonant-induced-f0-perturbation-in-kansai-japanese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an invited talk given at UTokyo Linguistics Colloquium.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study investigates the effect of voicing on onset F0 in Kansai Japanese. In tone languages, the effect of initial consonants on F0 tends to be smaller and shorter, hypothetically to maximize the tonal contrast preserved for lexical items. A recent study (Gao and Arai, 2019) found that despite Tokyo Japanese being a pitch-accent language, the consonant effect on F0 was not necessarily inhibited. However, this might be due to decreased laryngeal control in Tokyo Japanese because of its simple tonal contrast. Since the pitch accent system of Kansai Japanese is more complex than that of Tokyo Japanese, Kansai Japanese should show less F0 perturbation. In the experiment, five native speakers (4 females, 1 male) produced the target words /CVma/ (C: /n, b, p/, V: /i, a/) in different pitch accent types (HH, HL, LH) and focus conditions (broad, narrow, contrast focus). My data show that overall, F0 following /p/ is significantly higher. The more complex pitch-accent system did not lessen the F0 perturbation. Consistent across focus, the effect is slightly larger in words with a high pitch accent and in the high vowel /i/ context. This may be due to the congruence in laryngeal settings for high F0 production.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://miaozhang.org/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://miaozhang.org/publication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;journal-articles&#34;&gt;Journal articles&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(In preparation) ____ and Chodroff E. (2025). A crosslinguistic analysis of vowel-intrinsic F0&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(In preparation) Chodroff, E. and ____. (2025). A crosslinguistic analysis of vowel-intrinsic duration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(In preparation) ____. The preboundary lengthening of monophthongs and vowel sequences in Chinese, English and Japanese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(In preparation) ____ and Kiyono Fujinaga-Gordon. The production of voiceless nasals and information structure in Ikema&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(In preparation) Han, J-Y., Wang, T. and ____, (2025), Cross-linguistic influence in the acquisition of L3 stop consonants: A case study on the third language acquisition of Chinese by L1 Thai-L2 English learners&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Under review) ____, Fahardi-Pour, A., Baker, A., Ma J., Pricop, B. and Chodroff, E. (2025). Quantifying and Reducing Speaker Heterogeneity within the Common Voice Corpus for Phonetic Analysis, &lt;em&gt;Interspeech 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Under review) Chodroff, E., Fahardi-Pour, A., Baker, A., Ma J., ____, Pricop, B. and Pellegrino, E. (2025). An Audit of the Crowdsourced Validation Procedure in the Common Voice Corpus, &lt;em&gt;Interspeech 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Under review) Han, J-Y., Wang, T., Cao, Y-F. and ____. (2025). Cross-linguistic influence in the acquisition of L3 stop consonants: A case study on the third language acquisition of Chinese by L1 Spanish-L2 English learners, &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Multilingualism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Under review) ____ and Fujinaga-Gordon, F. (2025). An illustration of IPA: Ikema,&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Journal of International Phonetic Association&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Resubmitted) ____, Gong, S-X. and Guo, C-Y. (2025) Tone sandhi and tonal articulation in disyllabic sequences in Changsha Xiang, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Phonetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conferences&#34;&gt;Conferences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2025, with Chodroff E., A Crosslinguistic Analysis of Vowel Intrinsic F0. (Oral, &lt;strong&gt;peer-reviewed&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;em&gt;Phonetics and Phonology in Europe 6&lt;/em&gt;, June 25-27, Palma, Spain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2024, with Chodroff E., A Crosslinguistic Analysis of Intrinsic Vowel Duration. (Poster, &lt;strong&gt;peer-reviewed&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;em&gt;The 19th Conference on Laboratory Phonology (LabPhon19)&lt;/em&gt;, June 27-29, Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2023, A Cross-linguistic Study on Pre-boundary Vowel Lengthening (PBVL): Comparing monophthongs and diphthongs in Chinese, English, and Japanese. (Oral) &lt;em&gt;The 15th Phonetic Conference of China (PCC2023)&lt;/em&gt;, July 7-10, Shenzhen, Guangdong&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2022, Prosodic modulations on the formant excursions of diphthongs. (Poster) &lt;em&gt;The 183rd Meeting of the Acoustical Society of America (ASA183)&lt;/em&gt;, Dec 5-9, Nashville, TN&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2021, Positional tone sandhi in Changsha Xiang: A production study. (Poster, &lt;strong&gt;peer-reviewed&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;em&gt;The 1st International Conference on Tone and Intonation (TAI2021)&lt;/em&gt;, Dec 6-9, Sonderborg, Denmark and online&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2020, Effect of consonants on onset F0: Evidence from Kansai Japanese. (Poster) &lt;em&gt;Acoustics Virtually Everywhere (The 179th Meeting of the Acoustical Society of America)&lt;/em&gt;, Online.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2019, The role of information structure and foot structure on the kinematics of unstressed syllables. (Oral, &lt;strong&gt;peer-reviewed&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;em&gt;Hanyang International Symposium on Phonetics and Cognitive Sciences of Language (HISPhonCog) 2019&lt;/em&gt;, May 24-25, Seoul, South Korea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015, Japanese Lexical V-V compounds Revisited (Poster), &lt;em&gt;The Symposium of Challenging Japanese Language Teaching: Introducing the Efforts of University of Tsukuba&lt;/em&gt;, March, Tsukuba, Japan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013, On the Collocation of the Adverb ‘Zenzen’: An Investigation via Tsukuba Web Corpus (Poster), &lt;em&gt;The Annual Meeting of Association of Japanese Language and Japanese Language Pedagogy 2013, Tokyo, Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dissertation&#34;&gt;Dissertation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2022, Prosodic Influences on the Acoustics of Vowel Sequences, Department of Linguistics, New York State University at Buffalo. Advisor: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acsu.buffalo.edu/~cdicanio/&#34;&gt;Christian DiCanio&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://miaozhang.org/mz_dissertation.pdf&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
